Olufemi Adeojo

E-Mail: fadeojo@gmail.com

PROFILE

I possess well developed research, software, analytical and problem solving skills. I learn new technologies fast and enjoy working in a dynamic and fast paced high tech environment where innovation and customer satisfaction is the culture.

EDUCATION

Carleton University

[2006 - 2011]

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (Distinctions) (B.Eng.)

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

[2012]

Systems Engineering, Architecture, and Lifecycle Design (Short Programs)

Carleton University

[2015 - 2018]

Master of Computer Engineering (Distinctions) (M.Eng.)

SKILLS

- Frontend web development (React.js, JavaScript and Typescript)
- Server-side web development (Node.js and Elixir, SQL, NOSQL)
- Mobile application development (React Native, Flutter)
- DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes, Istio, Vault, AWS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Architect (Uberflip)

[Dec 2019 - Date]

I design and develop software systems and applications that help to deliver content for Uberflip customers. Technologies used are; AWS, Node.js, Typescript, JavaScript, SQL, Redis, Golang and Elixir.

Senior Platform Engineer (Prontoforms)

[Aug 2018 - Dec 2019]

I researched and implemented a microservice platform for current and new services using; AWS, Kubernetes (EKS), Docker, Istio, Hashicorp Vault, Opentracing, Sumologic and Nodejs.

Senior Software Engineer (Prontoforms)

[May 2017 - Aug 2018]

I developed and architected web client applications using ReactJS, redux and Mobx-state-tree. Research and influenced client and server application design decisions.



[February 2017 - April 2017]

I worked on a team that built the business intelligence application called Qlik Sense, using Node.js Typescript and Angularjs.

Full-stack Software Developer (Ciena)

[November 2013 - February 2017]

I work on the GUI of a network management application and a Kafka/WebSocket micro service using the phoenix framework.

- Web UI development using EmberJS
- Server-side development using Elixir and Phoenix Framework
- SDN development using Opendaylight and AngularJS

Software Developer (Freelance)

[March 2013 - August 2013]

I developed a teleconferencing application for tele-pharmacy using Adobe flash platform and other web technologies. I also worked on web application deployment and network management.

- Ruby on rails, HTML and CSS
- Adobe Flex framework

Software Developer (Alcatel-Lucent Canada)

[August 2012 - March 2013]

While at Alcatel-Lucent I worked as a Software developer on the WCE (Wireless Cloud Element) platform for wireless communication on cellular networks (UMTS).

- C and C++ development
- Cloud development

Software Developer (Avaya Canada)

[October 2011 - June 2012]

While at Avaya I worked as a Sr. java developer on a SOA (Service oriented application) called ACE (Agile Communication Environment). The technologies and methodologies I used are as follows:

- Java, JUnit Testing and JavaMail API (JEE)
- Web services REST and WSDL

Publications

• D.sattar, A. Matrawy. O. Adeojo "Adaptive Bubble Burst (ABB): Mitigating DDoS attacks in Software-Defined Networks", 17th International Telecommunications Network Strategy and Planning Symposium (Networks), pp. 50-55, Sept 2016.

REFERENCES

References available upon request.